Guide to the Lafayette Avenue Presbyterian Church records 2009.011
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Series 10: Elders and Administrators, 6.7 Linear Feet
  The series contains three sets of files pertaining to LAPC Elders and Administrators: Anna Colcord diaries (1928-1949), Wallace Dunbar Vincent papers (1887-1949), and the McWilliams family papers (1857-1973).
  - Sub-series 10.1: Anna L. Colcord diaries, 1925-1949; 0.3 Linear Feet in three folders
    Anna L. Colcord was a church Elder who served as the church's Executive Secretary. The sub-series consists of daily diaries maintained from 1925 to 1949.
    - Anna L. Colcord diaries (3 folders), 1925-1949 (Box 23, Folder 28-30)
  - Sub-series 10.2: Wallace Dunbar Vincent papers, 1887-1949; 0.4 Linear Feet in eight folders
    This sub-series contains material created by Wallace Dunbar Vincent, who was the church Assistant from the 1920s through the 1940s. He was an author who was sometimes published under the pseudonym Beech Hilton. The sub-series contains scrapbooks of his works, which include poetry, prose, games, and puzzles, dating from 1914 to the 1930s. Some of these writings were published in the weekly publication of the YMCA of Brooklyn. It also contains a 1949 Christmas card, featuring a portrait of Vincent.
    Wallace Dunbar Vincent was also involved in the LAPC's bible school, and school yearbooks which were produced by Vincent can be found in Series 14: Sunday School. Church publicity scrapbooks that were also produced by Vincent can be found in Series 17: Clippings.
    - Wallace Dunbar Vincent / Beech Hilton scrapbook front page, 1887-1895 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Wallace Dunbar Vincent / Beech Hilton scrapbook, 1914-1929 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Some Published Writings of Wallace Dunbar Vincent, 1924-1931 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Happy Valley Notes by Wallace Dunbar Vincent, 1927-1929 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Merry Games for Everyone by Wallace Dunbar Vincent, circa 1920s-1930s (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - The Merry Puzzle Book by Beech Hilton, circa 1920s-1930s (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Wallace Dunbar Vincent poems, 1940s (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Wallace Dunbar Vincent Christmas card, 1949 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Sub-series 10.3: McWilliams family papers, 1857-1973; 6 Linear Feet in four record cartons, one oversize flat box, and one custom box
    The sub-series contains papers relating to the McWilliams family, especially Helen McWilliams, and her father, Daniel W. McWilliams. Both Helen and Daniel served as Elders of the LAPC. The papers includes bibles, legal documents, correspondence, photographs, biographical files, and personal mementos, dating from 1857 to 1973.
    The sub-series includes a substantial amount of LAPC files that belonged to Helen McWilliams. These include files relating to the Women's Federation/Association and the Session, as well as sermons by Rev. George L. Knight. Helen's role as a member of the Vassar College alumni association is also documented in the sub-series.
    The papers were collected and maintained by Helen McWilliams, who upon her death donated the papers to the LAPC.
    - Daniel W. McWilliams - Book inscriptions, 1857-1906 (Box 29, Folder 28)
    - Daniel W. McWilliams' bibles, 1872, 1900s (Box 38, Folder -)
      Two bibles, one of which is inscribed to Daniel W. McWilliams from Rev. Moody (1872)
    - Daniel W. McWilliams legal documents, 1873, 1906 (Box 40, Folder -)
      Henry G. Marquand (1873) and Ira D. Sankey (1906)
    - Daniel W. McWilliams correspondence, 1875-1915 (Box 29, Folder 29)
      Includes Rev. Cuyler, Rev. Gregg, D.L. Moody, and family
    - McWilliams family portraits, 1878-1927 (Box 29, Folder 30)
    - Frederick Marquand, 1882-1901 (Box 40, Folder -)
      Includes will and memorial service
    - Daniel W. McWilliams missionary work, 1886-1957 (Box 29, Folder 31)
    - Daniel W. McWilliams - Common prayer book, circa 1890s (Box 29, Folder 32)
    - Lincoln's Gettysburg Address, 1894, 1909 (Box 29, Folder 33)
    - Daniel McWilliams biographies and memorials, 1890s-1919 (Box 29, Folder 34)
    - Rev. Cuyler letter, circa 1890s-1900s (Box 29, Folder 35)
      Found amongst Helen McWilliams' papers; page 3 only
    - Helen McWilliams photograph album, 1900s (Box 29, Folder 36)
    - Helen McWilliams dance group clippings, circa 1900 (Box 29, Folder 37)
    - Daniel W. McWilliams - Sunday school superintendent, 1900 (Box 29, Folder 38)
    - Helen M. McWilliams diaries and travel journals (11 volumes), 1902-1959 (Box 39, Folder -)
    - Daniel W. McWilliams - Brooklyn Public Library appointment, 1903 (Box 29, Folder 39)
      Signed by Mayor Seth Low
    - Vassar College Class of 1903 book (Box 38, Folder -)
    - Daniel W. McWilliams - Experimental subway train permit, 1904 (Box 29, Folder 40)
      Interborough Rapid Transit Company (IRT)
    - Helen M. McWilliams photographs (1 of 2), circa 1900s-1940s (Box 29, Folder 41)
    - Helen M. McWilliams photographs (2 of 2), circa 1900s-1940s (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Clarence A. McWilliams travel letters, 1910s (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - World Missionary Conference, Edinburgh, 1910 (Box 40, Folder -)
      Group photographs and notes by Helen M. McWilliams
    - Vassar songbook, circa 1910 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Helen M. McWilliams Red Cross papers, 1917-1919 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Clarence A. McWilliams framed French certificate, 1919 (Box 40, Folder -)
    - Helen F.M. McWilliams, 1919-1920 (Box 40, Folder -)
      Includes will
    - Helen M. McWilliams passports, 1926-1958 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Clarence A. McWilliams, 1927 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Helen M. McWilliams - Daughters of the American Revolution certificate, 1928 (Box 40, Folder -)
    - Helen M. McWilliams ephemera, 1931-1969 (Box 36, Folder 7)
      Includes D.L. Moody publication
    - Helen M. McWilliams - Coconut Grove photographs, 1936 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Helen M. McWilliams correspondence, 1937-1959 (Box 36, Folder 9)
      Includes Rev. Albert Lindsey Jr., Wilbert W. White, Rev. Cleland B. McAfee and his daughter
    - Henry Marquand's home, 1939 (Box 36, Folder 10)
      Fairfield Connecticut Tercentenary book
    - Helen M. McWilliams postcard/travel correspondence (2 envelopes), 1930s-1960s (Box 39, Folder -)
    - Helen M. McWilliams travel ephemera, 1930s-1960s (Box 39, Folder -)
    - Howard McWilliams, 1942 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Women's Federation scrapbook, 1945-1959 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Helen M. McWilliams recipe box, circa 1940s-1960s (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Helen M. McWillians Vassar reunion photographs, 1953-1963 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Elizabeth Field poetry books inscribed to Helen M. McWilliams, 1950s (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - Helen M. McWilliams ephemera, 1950s-1970s (Box 36, Folder 15)
      Includes Willoughby House Settlement
    - Helen M. McWilliams address book and letters, 1960s-1973 (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - Helen M. McWilliams - LAPC files, 1939-1962 (Box 36, Folder 17)
      Includes Women's Federation, bible study outlines, special event church bulletins, Outreach Committee, church renovation report, and Music Committee
    - Helen M. McWilliams - LAPC files, 1962-1969 (Box 36, Folder 18)
      Includes Women's Association, membership directories, and Session minutes
    - Helen M. McWilliams - LAPC files, 1963-1965 (Box 36, Folder 19)
      Includes church bulletins, Clarence Dickison material, United Presbyterian Residence, Theodore Yun-Kuk Kim, Elders, and Women's Association handbook
    - Helen M. McWilliams - LAPC files, 1963-1968 (Box 36, Folder 20)
      Includes Korea, organ and hymns, new members, stained glass windows, special messages and programs, history, Grace E. Brainaird Underwood Barton memorial, photographs, and Building Committee
    - Helen M. McWilliams - LAPC files, 1969-1970 (Box 36, Folder 21)
      Includes memoranda, Rev. Richard E. Ittner, 1969 annual report, Korean Congregation, Christian Education Committee, and a proposal for an experimental law office of an advocate attorney investigator as a specialized ministry instituted by the Presbytery of New York City
    - Helen M. McWilliams - LAPC files, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 22)
      Includes reports, minutes, memoranda, bulletins, Women's Association, and newsletters
    - Helen M. McWilliams - LAPC files, 1970-1971 (Box 36, Folder 23)
      Includes Rev. Richard Ittner, memoranda, reports, Women's Association, and Fort Greene
    - Helen M. McWilliams - LAPC files, 1971-1972 (Box 36, Folder 24)
      Includes stained glass windows, memoranda, annual report, and Women's Association
    - Helen M. McWilliams - Rev. Knight letters and sermons, 1960-1970 (Box 36, Folder 25)
      Also includes Edward P. Holden Jr. (President, Board of Trustees)
    - Helen M. McWilliams - Rev. Knight sermons, 1962-1965 (Box 36, Folder 26)
    - Helen M. McWilliams - Rev. Knight sermons, 1969-1970 (Box 36, Folder 27)
      Includes one sermon by Rev. Richard Ittner
    - Helen M. McWilliams 75 year membership celebration photographs, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 28)
      with Rev. Knight
    - Helen M. McWilliams 75 year membership celebration audio reels, 1970 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Helen M. McWilliams 75 year membership celebration scrapbook, 1970 (Box 38, Folder -)
      Includes photographs of the McWilliams family and several LAPC pastors
    - Helen M. McWilliams memorial service, 1973 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Helen M. McWilliams Vassar alumni papers (7 folders), 1960-1973 (Box 37, Folder 3-9)
- Series 11: Music and organ, 1880-1995; 1.25 Linear Feet in 36 folders
  Contains files relating to the LAPC's Ministry of Music, including items related to its organ, its musical director and choir, concerts, and its Cultural Crossroads programs, dating from 1880 to 1995. It includes one file of material on musical director and organist John Hyatt Brewer, which contains his original contract with the church, along material related to celebrations in his honor, photographic portraits, and other documents. Material related to the church's organ includes a contract and correspondence with organ manufacturers Hook and Hastings (1886-1892) and specifications and other documents related to a new organ, which was installed in 1910. A letter from former pastor David Gregg to then-current pastor Cleland B. McAfee regarding the church's music and new organ is included in the series (1910). The series also contains sheet music, including a book of music composed by Dudley Buck and owned by soprano Elizabeth Tudor (1880). Finally, the series includes five scrapbooks containing clippings and programs relating to concerts at the LAPC, as well as other Brooklyn churches and clubs (1870-1895).
  Additional concert and choir performance programs and announcements can be found in Series 1: Church Bulletins and Series 4: Scrapbooks.
  - Music scrapbooks (5 folders), 1870-1895 (Box 22, Folder 7-11)
  - "Ye Juvenile Olde Folke" in ye Greate Concerte program, 1880 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    Includes an invitation to "Singing Nyghte offe ye Juvnile Olde Folke" (1880) and letter regarding the donation of invitation to the church (1940)
  - Elizabeth Tudor, 1880-1928 (Box 34, Folder -)
    Oversize; includes correspondence, clippings, portrait, brochure, and copy of "Golden Legend" sheet music by Dudley Buck which belonged to Tudor
  - John H. Brewer, 1881-1931 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Hook and Hastings organ contract and correspondence, 1886-1892 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Various sheet music, circa 1880s-1990 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Organ work correspondence, 1892 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Choir clipping, 1893 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Marie Vaw choir resignation, 1895 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Loose scrapbook page, circa 1890s (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Group photograph of music director and choir with church organ, circa 1890s-1910s (Box 40, Folder -)
  - Sheet music with handwritten notation by John H. Brewer, circa 1890s-1930 (Box 34, Folder -)
  - Choir contracts, 1905 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Madam Butterfly songbook (German version), 1907 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Letter from Gregg to McAfee regarding music and organ, 1910 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - New organ specifications, correspondence, and dedication, 1910 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Organ blueprint, circa 1910 (Box 34, Folder -)
  - Music budget, 1932 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Clippings, 1932-1969 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Reception to Dr. Karg-Elert by the American Guild of Organists - Dedication of the New Moeller Organ in the Grand Ballroom of Hotel Waldorf-Astoria group photograph, 1932 (Box 40, Folder -)
  - Voice of Music - Mr. Croswell, 1957 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Other churches, 1957-1969 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Clarence Dickison - The Brick Church concert program and clipping, 1959 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Organ card, 1959 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Church organ - edited negative and print, circa 1960s (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - "God Save the Queen", circa 1960s (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Lilian Carpenter F.A.G.O. performs at the Austin Organ of LAPC - LP record sleeve, 1969 (Box 34, Folder -)
    Oversize; record is missing
  - Concert programs/flyers and Ministry of Music booklets, 1969-1985 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Alma Ketchell Yodel correspondence, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    Former choir soloist
  - Dr. Melville Charlton, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    Church organist; includes photographic prints and negative
  - Guidelines for a Vital and Creative Ministry of Music, 1975-1980 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Hymnal supplement, circa 1970s (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Cultural Crossroads and other concerts, 1987-1996 (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Hampson A. Sisler organ songbooks (signed), 1990-1994 (Box 23, Folder 27)
- Series 12: Building and property records, circa 1870s-2003; 0.25 Linear Feet in 15 folders
  The series contains building and property records, dating from 1881 to 2003. Of note are property deeds, images of the church and other buildings, visitor guides that provide detailed information on the church building's history, and records and photographs related to the church's stained glass Tiffany windows.
  - 302 Cumberland Street, 1962-1963 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Architecture manuscript, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Border Mission Sabbath School / Olivet property, 1901 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Building maintenance, 1912-1937 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Church and building images, circa 1890s-1964 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Church interior photographs, circa 1870s, 1960s (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Cuyler Church, 1906-1907 (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - Deeds and mortgages, 1881-1939 (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - First Presbyterian Church of Brooklyn, 1960s (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - Gladys Underwood James Memorial Garden, 1970s (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - Irondale Esemble project proposal, 2003 (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous, 1899-1960 (Box 25, Folder 27)
  - Visitor guides, 1970s-1990s (Box 25, Folder 28)
  - Windows and tablets, 1897-1979 (Box 25, Folder 29)
    Includes historical timelines
  - Window photographs, circa 1960s (Box 25, Folder 30)
  - Windows / Re-building campaign, 1998-2003 (Box 25, Folder 31)
- Series 13: Mission work, 1886-circa 2000s; 0.4 Linear Feet
  The series contains files relating to LAPC mission work in Kentucky and Korea, dating from 1886 to circa 2000s.
  Organized into two sub-series:
  Sub-series 13.1: Buckhorn Association
  Sub-series 13.2: Underwood family and Korean Congregation
  - Sub-series 13.1: Buckhorn Association, 1909-circa 2000s; 0.2 Linear Feet in 12 folders
    The series contains files relating to the Buckhorn Association, dating from 1909 to the 2000s. It includes photographs, publications, clippings, and meeting minutes.
    - Witherspoon College and Buckhorn photographs, 1909 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Buckhorn Association publications, circa 1920-1972 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Clippings and reprints, 1922-1964 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Financial records, 1924-1948 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Rev. Harvey S. Murdoch portrait, 1932 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Buckhorn Presbyterian Church notecard - Mrs. Crit Keen correspondence, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Annual meeting minutes, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Buckhorn, Kentucky slides by Elmber E. Gabbard, circa 1960s (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Historical notes, circa 1960s-1990s (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Lincoln Day Luncheon - February 11, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Tax exempt application, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 29)
      Includes by-laws and meeting minutes
    - Harvey S. Murdoch Society / Buckhorn Children's Foundation reproduction photographs, circa 2000s (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Sub-series 13.2: Underwood family and Korean Congregation, 1886-circa 1990s; 0.2 Linear Feet in 14 folders
    The series documents the Underwood family, their missionary work in Korea, and Korean cogregations in New York City, dating from 1886 to the 1990s. The records include publications, clippings, photographs, correspondence, sermons, and biographical files on the Underwoods.
    - Korean mission correspondence, 1886, 1907 (Box 16, Folder 31a)
    - Horace G. Underwood Korea lecture tickets, 1902 (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - The Assembly Herald vol. XV no. 1, 1909 (Box 16, Folder 33)
      Regarding missionary work
    - Underwood children in Korean garb photograph, circa 1910s (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - The Finished Task, 1917 (Box 16, Folder 34)
      Foreign missionary booklet with profile of Horace Grant Underwood
    - Korea missionary publications, 1922-1958 (Box 16, Folder 35)
    - Grace B. Underwood birthday menu, 1927 (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - Underwood-Korea articles and clippings, 1928-1969 (Box 16, Folder 37)
      Includes material written by Ethel and Horace B. Underwood
    - Seoul Union Church Thanksgiving Day sermon by Horace H. Underwood, 1932 (Box 16, Folder 38)
    - John Thomas Underwood, 1935-1959 (Box 16, Folder 39)
      Includes biographical booklet, portraits (prints and negatives), giant Underwood typewriter postcard, and a letter regarding donations to the church by his widow Grace V. Barton.
    - Underwood family biographical, circa 1940s-1990s (Box 16, Folder 40)
    - Ethel Underwood death, 1949-1950 (Box 16, Folder 41)
    - Horace H. Underwood death, 1950-1951 (Box 16, Folder 42)
    - Letter from Lt. Richard F. Underwood to Grace Underwood, 1950 (Box 16, Folder 43)
    - Centennial Celebration sermon by James H. Underwood, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 44)
    - Brooklyn Korean congregation, 1964-1988 (Box 16, Folder 45)
    - Underwood family portrait, circa 1970s (Box 16, Folder 46)
- Series 14: Sunday School, 1865-1996; 2 Linear Feet in three record cartons
  The series contains files relating to the Sunday School (also referred to as the Sabbath School and the Bible School) at the LAPC, dating from 1865 to 1996. The records include reports, record books, yearbooks, photographs, and teaching materials. The bulk of the series is composed of yearbooks, which document the activities of the Bible School from 1928 to 1950. These yearbooks were assembled by Wallace Dunbar Vincent, a church administrator who was the Bible School secretary during this period.
  - Sunday School reports, 1865-1913 (Box 23, Folder 31)
    Includes building report and Sunday School Missionary Association
  - Sunday School record book, 1872 (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - Sunday School record book, 1876-1884 (Box 23, Folder 33)
  - Sunday School programs, bookmarks, and other ephemera, 1879-1911 (Box 23, Folder 34)
    Includes Brooklyn Sunday School Union
  - Officers and teachers of the Sabbath School honor Major Thomas Harwood, 1889 (Box 23, Folder 35)
  - Sunday School lesson book, 1905 (Box 23, Folder 36)
  - Young Women's Bible Class, circa 1920s (Box 23, Folder 37)
  - Bible School group portrait, 1928 (Box 34, Folder -)
    Oversize; with notes and poem by Wallace Dunbar Vincent
  - Bible School yearbook - Vol. 1, 1928-1929 (Box 23, Folder 38)
  - Bible School yearbooks - Vol. 2-9, 12-14, 1929-1940 (Box 24, Folder 1-11)
    Volumes 10 and 11 are missing
  - Bible School yearbooks - Vol. 15-20, 22-24, 1940-1950 (Box 25, Folder 1-9)
    Volume 21 is missing
  - Aids to worship for the church school, circa 1960s (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Confirmation class, 1989-1990 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Sunday School, 1990 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Sunday School picnic, 1996 (Box 25, Folder 13)
- Series 15: Young People's Association, circa 1868-1945; 0.3 Linear Feet in 11 folders
  Contains items related to the LAPC Young People's Association (YPA), including a meeting book (circa 1868-1873), manuals (1880-1913), event programs and fliers (1886-1916), photographs of the YPA fair (1892 and 1894), meeting attendance statistics (1900-1909), two pieces of correspondence (1905 and 1919), two Junior YPA advisory committee reports (1907), election tickets (1917-1919), an annual report (1918-1919), one newsletter (1927), and a revised constitution (1945).
  - YPA meeting book, circa 1868-1873 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - YPA programs and flyers, 1886-1916 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - YPA fair photograph, 1892 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - YPA fair photographs, 1894 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - YPA meeting attendance, 1900-1909 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - YPA correspondence, 1905, 1919 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Junior YPA advisory committee reports, 1907 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - YPA tickets, 1917-1919 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    Used for executive elections
  - YPA annual report, 1918-1919 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - "Sparks from the Hearth" newsletter, 1927 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Constitution of the YPA, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 18)
- Series 16: War service records, 1918-1946; 0.3 Linear Feet in five folders
  The series contains records relating to LAPC members' service during World War I and World War II. It includes one newspaper clipping (1918), war service questionnaires (1918-1919, 1946), and two copies of a published volume entitled Lafayette Avenue Presbyterian Church World War Honor Roll, which documents the role of church members in World War I (1921).
  - World War I clipping, 1918 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - War service records (2 folders), 1918-1919 (Box 16, Folder 5-6)
  - World War Honor Roll, 1921 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - War service records, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - "To the Boys in Service" poem by Wallace Dunbar Vincent, circa 1940s (Box 16, Folder 8a)
- Series 17: Clippings, 1862-2000; 0.4 Linear Feet in 12 folders
  The series contains publicity clipping scrapbooks, which were assembled by Wallace Dunbar Vincent (1930-1935); loose clippings relating to the church (1870s-2000); one file containing profiles of church members published in Newsday (1990); and one bound volume of the Brooklyn City News (January-June 1862), which contains an article on the the dedication of LAPC's building in March 1862.
  - Church Publicity (5 folders), 1930-1935 (Box 27, Folder 1-5)
  - Clippings (5 folders), 1870s-2000 (Box 27, Folder 6-10)
    Includes The Quill, vol. 1 no. 9 (1893)
  - Member profiles, 1990 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Oversize clippings, 1872, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Brooklyn City News bound volume (January-June), 1862 (Box 43, Folder -)
    Includes an article on the LAPC's building dedication (March 1862)
- Series 18: Photographs, 1890s-2002
  The series contains photographs (primarily prints) dating from the 1890s to 2002. Church social activities and groups are well represented in the collection (such as the Girl Scouts, Boy Scouts, and dramatic groups). Pastors Magary and Knight also feature prominently in the series. This series also includes one digital file, a digitized version of an early 1900s photograph of a woman and child.